vodafone.co.nz 2019-10-17

# Privacy policy - Vodafone NZ

Vodafone New Zealand Limited (“our, we or us”) is committed to protecting your personal information. We have created this Privacy Policy to help you understand how we collect, use and protect your information when you visit our web and WAP sites and use our products and services.

If you want to talk to us about this policy or any concerns or queries you have about the use of your personal information, please email us at [customer.privacy@vodafone.com](mailto:customer.privacy@vodafone.com "customer.privacy@vodafone.com")

This policy is provided for your information and doesn’t limit or exclude your rights under the Privacy Act 1993 or the Telecommunications Information Privacy Code 2003.

**1\. What information does Vodafone collect?**

We collect information relating to you that you have provided to us (for example, on an application or registration form, when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by us or through the way you use our products and services) or that we may have obtained from another source (such as our suppliers or from marketing organisations and credit agencies). Where possible, we will collect the information directly from you. However the method of collecting this information may vary depending on which one of our services you are using (for example our mobile services or our internet services).

This information may include, your name, address, telephone numbers, information on how you use our products and services (such as the type, date, time, location and duration of calls or messages, the numbers you call, how much you spend, and information on you and the browsing and viewing activity that happens while you use internet services (including the internet sites and pages visited, your Internet Protocol (IP) address and the dates and times you or anyone using your internet services logs on and off, and the channels accessed through your TV services with us)), the location of your mobile phone, lifestyle information and any other information collected in relation to your use of our products and services. This information may be held by us while you are using our services and for a period of time afterwards, but only for so long as we are legally entitled to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We may also monitor and record your calls to us and our calls to you.

**2\. How does Vodafone use your information?**

The information that we collect from you may be used by us for a number of purposes connected with our business such as:

2.1 processing and evidencing your orders or applications;

2.2 carrying out credit checking and scoring (unless we have agreed otherwise);

2.3 providing you with products and/or services you have requested or administering your account;

2.4 billing you (unless you pay by another agreed method) and collecting any debt owed to us by you;

2.5 settling accounts with those who provide related services to us;

2.6 dealing with your requests, enquiries or complaints and other customer care related activities;

2.7 carrying out market and product analysis, and improvements to our products and services;

2.8 contacting you about our group companies’ products and services and the products and services of carefully selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you (unless you ask us in writing not to). Where such contact is via electronic means, you agree that the electronic marketing messages we and our selected third parties send don’t need to include an unsubscribe facility;

2.9 registering your details and allocating or offering you rewards, discounts or other benefits and fulfilling any requests or requirements you may have in respect of our group companies’ loyalty or reward programmes and other similar schemes;

2.10 carrying out any activity in connection with a legal, governmental or regulatory requirement on us or in connection with legal proceedings, crime or fraud prevention, detection or prosecution;

2.11 carrying out activities connected with the running of our business such as personnel training, quality control, network monitoring, testing and maintenance of computer and other systems and in connection with the transfer of any part of our business in respect of which you are a customer or a potential customer;

2.12 generally customising your experience on our sites;

2.13 for general administrative and business purposes.

**3\. Sharing your information**

There may be times when we need to disclose your personal information to third parties (some of which may be based outside of New Zealand). If we do this, we will only disclose your information to:

3.1 our group companies who may use and disclose your information for the same purposes as us;

3.2 those who provide to us or our group companies products or services that support the services that we provide, such as our dealers and suppliers;

3.3 other network operators to enable you to make and receive calls through other networks, so we can transfer numbers from one network to another and to monitor or investigate fraud or other offences.

3.4 credit reference agencies (unless we have agreed otherwise), who may share your information with other organisations and who may keep a record of the searches we make against your name;

3.5 debt collection agencies or companies, in order to collect any money owing by you in respect of an unpaid Vodafone bill;

3.6 if someone else pays your bill, such as your employer, that person;

3.7 those providing telephone and similar directories or directory enquiry services and other such publicly available databases and publications, except where you have specifically directed us not to;

3.8 anyone we transfer our business to in respect of which you are a customer or a potential customer;

3.9 Kogan.com Holdings Pty Ltd in order to enable them to provide you with a new Kogan SIM card, if required;

3.10 Digital Mobile Limited in order to enable them to manage operations within Vodafone retail stores and provide **you with** Vodafone interest free and bill payment services instore.

3.11 anyone who assists us in protecting the operation of the Vodafone networks and systems, including the use of monitoring and detection in order to identify potential threats, such as hacking and virus dissemination and other security vulnerabilities;

3.12 anyone who hosts or maintains data centres, service platforms and other infrastructure and systems on behalf of us and our group companies, where your information is processed;

3.13 persons to whom we may be required to pass your information by reason of legal, governmental or regulatory authority including law enforcement agencies and emergency services;

3.14 other service providers in relation to a service used through our network to allow that service to be charged to you;

3.15 aggregated user statistics and other information that does not personally identify you, to third parties such as our advertisers, customers, potential customers and partners;

3.16 any person or organisation as authorised by the Privacy Act 1993 and/or the Telecommunications Information Privacy Code 2003, including with your prior authorisation which we will usually obtain at the time of collecting the information from you.

3.17 other people who you specifically request we share your account information with – (for example, by you ‘authorising’ them on your account or by you sharing access via ‘My Vodafone’).

If you have not opted out of receiving marketing material from us, we may also provide your personal information to carefully selected third parties who we reasonably believe provide products or services that may be of interest to you and who have contracted with Vodafone to keep the information confidential, or who are subject to obligations to protect your personal information.

If you would like to opt-out of receiving Vodafone marketing materials, please contact 777 from your Vodafone mobile or go to My Vodafone at www.vodafone.co.nz. Even if you opt out, Vodafone will still need to send you essential information about your account or changes to your plans or service.

Some of our message services and selected user initiated service queries, are available to you free of charge.  If you use one of these free services to request or send a message, you or the recipient of that message may receive third party advertising with the requested message, even if you or the recipient have opted out of receiving marketing messages from us.

**4\. Using Products and services outside New Zealand**

If you wish to use our products or services outside New Zealand, your information may be transferred outside New Zealand to that country. Our websites and systems and those of our group companies may also be based on servers located outside of New Zealand. Please note that the data protection and other laws of countries outside New Zealand may not be as comprehensive as the laws of this country.

**5\. Protecting your personal information**

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date and stored in a secure environment protected from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

If you choose callerID restriction we will prevent your number being shown on any receiver. Your number may still be displayed to emergency or other services, when you send a TXT message and to us.  Where you do not choose to use callerID restriction, your number may be displayed to the person you have called or sent a message to.

**6\. Accessing and updating your personal information**

You have the right to access personal information about you if we hold that personal information in a way that it can be readily retrieved, subject to some exceptions provided at law.

You may request access to the personal information we hold about you by sending an email to  [customer.privacy@vodafone.com](mailto:customer.privacy@vodafone.com "customer.privacy@vodafone.com") Please quote your name and address. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of what information you want a copy (this helps us to more readily locate your data).

In some cases, there may be a charge associated with providing copies of your personal information to you. If so, we will advise you of this prior to sending your information to you.

We will not be able to provide you personal information if we do not know or don’t have reasonable grounds to believe it is personal information about you or if disclosing the information would involve the unwarranted disclosure of the affairs of another individual.

You can request correction or amendment of the information held by us at any time and as often as necessary by sending us an e-mail to  [Contacting us](mailto:customer.privacy@vodafone.com "Contacting us") and specifying the information that you require changed. If it is reasonable in the circumstances for us to do so, we will make the requested change or correction, otherwise we’ll take reasonable steps to mark that information as having been subject to a change or correction request.

For further information about New Zealand's Privacy Act 1993 and how it protects the personal information of individuals in New Zealand, see www.privacy.org.nz.

Some of our services are password-protected so that only you have access to your personal information. You should not reveal your password to other people and you should change it regularly. Vodafone will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. Also, if you are using the internet, remember to sign out of your Vodafone account and close your browser window when you have finished. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place.

**7\. Internet use**

We make every effort to maintain the security of our internet connections; however for reasons outside of our control, security risks may still arise. Any personal information transmitted to us or from our online products or services will therefore be at your own risk, however we will use our best efforts to ensure that any such information remains secure. We cannot protect any information that you make available to the general public – for example, on message boards or in chat rooms.

Please note that when you are accessing a non-Vodafone website, you should always read their privacy policy or website terms and conditions – especially if you are considering providing them with your personal information. You are also responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information.

We may use cookies and other interactive techniques such as web beacons to collect non-personal information about how you interact with our website, and web-related products and services, to:

7.1 understand what you like and use about our website;

7.2 understand what you do not like and do not use on our website;

7.3 provide a more enjoyable, customised service and experience,

7.4 enable you to use certain services on our website; and

7.5 help us develop and deliver better products and services tailored to our customers’ interests and needs.

We also collect IP addresses. IP addresses are assigned to computers on the internet to uniquely identify them within the global network. We collect and manage IP addresses as part of the service of providing internet session management and for security purposes.

We may use a persistent cookie to record details such as a unique user identity and general registration details on your PC. This helps us recognise you on subsequent visits to this website so that you don’t have to re-enter your registration details each time you visit us and allows us to carry out the activities mentioned above.

Most browser technology (such as Internet Explorer, Safari, Chrome etc)  allows you to choose whether to accept cookies or not – you can either refuse all cookies or you can set your browser to alert you each time that a website tries to set a cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to access our sites, but you may need them for customisable areas of the site that we may develop in the future, or to access and benefit from certain functionality offered by the site.

**8\. Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and we will tell you about a change in the policy by posting an updated policy on our website. Any change we make applies from the date we post it on the website.
